# KINGSLEY ENEJA

# **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

Federal Capital, Abuja, Nigeria | +2348109037816 | eneja.kc@gmail.com | Github | Website | LinkedIn

## **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I am a full stack software engineer with a degree in computer engineering and over 5 years of professional experience. I specialise in architecting, designing and developing highly scalable software systems, building monitoring tools to ensure there are not downtimes and implementing disaster recovery strategies.

Through years of experience, I have developed a keen eye for efficiency, consistency and simplicity in software, combined with an ability to collaborate with others to identify the best solution to complex problems.

#### **TECH STACK**

Back End Web Development:

Node, Express, NestJs, REST APIs, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MongoDB, Golang, Docker, Kubernetes, Typescript, Python (flask)

Front End Web Development:

HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, React, Redux, Javascript, Typescript, Jquery

Test Frameworks:

Jest, Mocha, Jasmine, Enzyme

Web Design Tools:

Figma

### **EXPERIENCE**

Getir (Europe) | Senior Backend Engineer | May 2021 - Present

 Working with the team responsible for promotions, advertisement and retention; Responsible for refactoring codebase to eliminate technical depth; Optimizing existing software to improve response time and general application performance; developing new services as well as maintaining existing ones.

Lighthouse Labs (Canada) | Software Engineering Mentor | October 2021 - Present

 Providing Technical (and moral) support to software engineering interns and bootcampers

Access Bank | Senior Software Engineer | Dec 2019 - May 2021

- Designed and lead the development of account maintenance software for reporting account-related activities to the Central bank of Nigeria in real-time.
- Designed and implemented the backend server for a payment gateway for both merchants and aggregators.

Andela | Software Engineer | Dec 2018 - Oct 2019

• Worked on the VOF application - an Andela application that streamlines the decision making process in hiring software engineers at Andela.

Erregen Technology | Software Engineer (Contract) | Aug 2017 - April 2020

 Designing and implementing backend servers. Worked on Health insurance management software for the military, and a Ship maintenance Software for the Nigerian Navy

# NASRDA | Intern Engineer | Apr 2015 - Oct 2015

• NASRDA: National Space Research and Development Agency

## **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

- B.Eng. Computer Engineering
  GPA 4.46 / 5.0
  Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka, Anambra State, Nigeria
- Advanced SQL for Data Scientists Udacity
- Applied Data Science I: Scientific Computing & Python WorldQuant University
- Front End Web Development Certification Andela Learning Community
- Expert Html, CSS and Javascript Pluralsight
- Responsive Web Design Certification FreeCodeCamp